Himani Makode

Programmer Analyst I - Baylor College of Medicine

Houston, TX - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Himani-Makode/9cbdfe35ba914c2c

Over 2 years of experience in web development including interacting with clients and understanding the requirements,

analysis, design, development, testing, and implementation of code and applications. Demonstrated ability to complete

projects in deadline-oriented environments

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Sponsorship required to work in the US

WORK EXPERIENCE

Programmer Analyst I

Baylor College of Medicine - Houston, TX - June 2016 to Present

Developed web applications using C#.NET and ASP.NET as frontend and MS SQL server as backend database

- Designed back-end database architecture using UML class diagram and developed database using stored procedures, SQL and triggers
- Contributed to design and development of client and server database applications from the design phase to implementation, testing and maintenance
- Created mappings to extract data from SQL Server and to migrate and transform data from Text/Access/ Excel

Spreadsheet using SQL Server Integration Service (SSIS)

Data Analyst Intern

Mercuria Energy Trading Incorporation - Houston, TX - August 2015 to November 2015

Performed ETL on the real-time data received from industries (ERCOT, TransGas, MISO Energy, EIA, GDSR) on daily basis using Tableau, Java, and Spring Framework, SAX Parser

- Created Processor java class file depending on the type of file (HTML, XML, CSV, XLS, TEXT) which read the data, parse the data of different file type and load into the SQL Server Management Studio tables
- Data Analysis with Business analytics tool Tableau, maintained Tableau Portal, access an environments

Web Designer

University of Houston - Clear Lake - May 2015 to August 2015

Designed and maintained office of online programs website (GUI, and Backend) using Adobe Photoshop, CSS, and HTML Website: http://prtl.uhcl.edu/portal/page/portal/PRV/OnlinePrograms/Online_Programs

Software Developer Intern

HCL CDC - IN - June 2013 to July 2013

Created e-commerce shopping website using PHP, MySQL, and Java Script for the client, providing the facility to add products in shopping cart, checking status of product delivery, and PayPal payment system

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Computer Science in Computer Science

University of Houston Clear Lake - Houston, TX August 2014 to May 2016

Bachelor of Engineering in Information Technology in Information Technology

Rajiv Gandhi Technical University August 2010 to June 2014

SKILLS

.NET (1 year), ASP (1 year), MS SQL server (1 year), SQL (1 year), SQL server (1 year)

LINKS

http://www.linkedin.com/in/himanimakode/en

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

TECHINICAL SKILLS

Web Design: HTML, CSS, XML, JavaScript, jQuery Database: MS SQL Server, MySQL, MS Access

Programming: Java, C#, ASP.NET, VB .NET, Angular JS 2

Development Tools: Dreamweaver, Visual Studio

Business Analytics Software: Tableau

Methodologies: Agile

Testing: Selenium Automated Testing